the staff here was um highly
complimentary of how um their pre-draft
stuff with you was. I mean, when did you
meet with them and how did your
interactions with them kind of unfold?
>> Yes. Uh you know, I had a I had a
meeting with them um you know, earlier
this month, I would say. Actually, not
earlier, not really not too long ago. Um
you know, probably like maybe a week and
some change ago. um you know went up
there to the visit and I had a great
time just talking with the staff you
know bonded with a lot of them uh you
know just personalitywise and just
connecting on a personal level not even
talking about football which is
something I loved and I feel like I can
be myself you know in their building
that was something that was really
important um but I was very grateful for
the opportunity um and then you know
talking football just the way that you
know they approach the game and how they
go about their culture and everything
like that is something that um you know
I'm very excited about and I'm glad I'm
a Falcon
What are your feelings right now?
>> Man, I'm feeling blessed, man. That's
that's that's the only word that's
really coming to my mind. Um, you know,
it was it was a crazy process, stressful
process, honestly. Um, but, you know,
everything happens at the right times
and on God's timing. So, uh, you know,
very, very blessed for the opportunity
that they've given me and very
appreciative that, um, you know, they're
believe in me and believe in my
abilities that I can bring to the
organization.
>> Congratulations, man. It's good to have
you around still and uh super going from
Georgia to here just what uh how can you
put into words and kind of describe what
that moment was when you get the call
and you see it's the Falcons.
>> Yeah, it was surreal. Um you know, just
because of how everything, you know, has
been transpiring, everything like that.
Um you know, and and just waiting on
your name to get called and you really
never know. Um and that's and that's the
thing. But it was just crazy. I was
actually uh you know, I'm miked up and
things like that. I'm like, "Hey man,
like can you take my mic off for a
couple minutes or whatever the case is?"
Um, then I start getting the call. I saw
the area code. I said, "Whoa, is this a
Georgia?" I said, "Fuck my mic back up,
man." So, we we had to we had to do that
real quick. But, um, you know, it was
just special just because, you know, my
brother has another year at Georgia as
well. Um, you know, it's easy for my
parents to be able to watch both games.
Um, so, so that just shows how God
works. Um, you know, and I'm meant to be
in Atlanta.
Zachariah, um,
it seemed like you went a little later
than a lot of people were expecting and
you mentioned maybe this is a little
kind of a tough day. What was it like to
to be waiting and to not know when you
might go and probably just see other
receivers go before you?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I I just trust in
God's plan so much. I mean, I wasn't
really harping on, oh, this guy's going
before me, this, this, and that. Um, you
know, I got to know that God has a plan
for my life. Um, and my my journey is
gonna be different than everyone else's.
So really just keeping that focus um you
know leaning on my family and allowing
them to you know continuously help me
understand that um you know emphasizing
that even though I already do but very
straight uh faithled family um you know
we very based off that. So really just
focus on that. Um you know wherever
wherever I ended up landing I knew that
it was going to be on on God's timing
and uh you know he showed me once again
that um you know he'll always put me in
the right positions at the right times.
>> Zach do you know uh do you know Drake
London at all?
>> Yes sir. is actually crazy. Um, you
know, I've been knowing him for for some
years now, which is pretty crazy. Um,
and I actually got a chance to talk to
him not too long ago before the draft.
And I actually talked to him and Bean
um, you know, not too long ago. They
facetimed me and everything like, "Hey
man, I Jake was like, I was telling you,
I was telling you, um, he's a great
player and even a better person as well.
Um, so I'm really excited just to learn
from him. um you know, he's very
successful in this league and um I'm
very excited to learn, you know, under
him as a rookie and he's been through
the ins and outs of of the team and in
the NFL as well. So, very excited to,
you know, be be a partner um a
partnership in his room for sure.
>> Has coach Sansky talked to you a little
bit about like what kind of role they
see you playing this team?
>> Um just trying to be a playmaker
overall. You know, wherever they want me
to be, you know, offense, special teams,
whatever it is, I'm willing to do
whatever it takes.
How do you think your skill set's going
to apply now to the NFL level?
Obviously, I think last year at Georgia,
we saw a lot whether it was screens at
the line of scrimmage, everything like
that. How do you think uh you'll be able
to, you know, elevate all your skill
sets here to the next level?
>> Yes, I'm very excited. Um, you know,
very blessed to be in this opportunity.
Um, you know, in a system like the
Atlanta Falcons, you know, had great
visits with the receiver coaches and,
you know, just talking football is very,
uh, you know, I would say similar to
Georgia. So, I don't think it's going to
be too much of a transition wise. Uh,
given that like a lot of NFL teams use
like the same terminology and things
like that, but Atlanta's pretty similar
to Georgia. So, I'm very excited about
that. Um, and just excited to see what
the coaches uh, you know, want to do,
what positions they want to put me in.
>> Zachariah, I wonder, forgive me, the
conversation with Drake and Bejian, did
that happen before the draft or did that
happen today after you got picked?
>> Yes, it happened today. Um, you know, I
was getting a lot of calls and texts
right after. Um, but I saw something
said Bejan in there and then I had to
after I did the first Zoom or whatever,
I typed up Bejian in my messages so I
didn't like have to scroll to find it
and I clicked the message and it was
Drake and Bejian like hey like we're
excited for you to come um be a Falcon
and things like that and they FaceTime
me but I missed their call. So had to
call them back. Um you know they were
excited and pumped up uh you know
getting me out there with them boys and
I was just telling like it's an honor
you know to be on the offense with you
guys and shoot I'm ready to go to work
right now.
>> What do you think the this offense is
capable of doing? You Drake Van Kyle all
these guys like what what what's the
ceiling for you guys?
>> I think it's going to be great. Um you
know a lot of those guys are are high
character and high talented players as
well. um you know, so that's something
I'm really looking forward to and that's
something that I love to be around
like-minded players and people who are
striving to be the best versions of
themselves um and ultimately help the
team as best as possible as well. So, I
think the offense could definitely be
special. Um and I'm excited to see what
what transpires this season.
>> Zachariah, um sorry, uh welcome to
Atlanta. Uh the Falcons have a a good
story history at wide receiver. I'm
curious when you were, you know, growing
up, were you familiar with with the
Falcons? Did you pay attention to Rody
White, Julio Jones, Calvin Ridley, those
guys?
>> Oh, yeah, definitely. Um, like you said,
there's a lot of guys, um, you know, who
who have been successful in the NFL. Um,
like you said, Julio Jones and Calvin
Ridley's, a lot of those guys like that
have been able to pave the way for the
Falcons. And it's actually crazy. I'm
kind of getting off topic a little bit,
but Matt Ryan, watching him growing up
was something that's pretty crazy to me.
And to be able to just, you know, be in
an organization with him is is pretty
special as well. just want to get a
chance to learn from him and hopefully I
can tap back into those those greats who
came through Atlanta, especially at the
wide receiver position as well to learn
a little bit of something as I step into
the league.
>> Zachariah, I wonder if you were
concerned that the incident on Sunday
was going to affect your draft position
at all. Did just the timing of that.
Were you anxious about that this week at
all?
>> No, I wasn't anxious. Uh if you look at
the the things of what transpired then
you'll understand why I wasn't anxious.
>> Right. And the Ian and Coach Depaskansky
said that didn't affect the way they
felt about you at all. Was that what you
heard from most teams as?
>> Uh, yes. I've heard that from from every
team. Nobody was concerned. Um, you
know, they know who I am as a person and
the character that I hold myself of. Um,
and and I think that that was pretty
much self-explanatory given the report
and everything.
>> Yeah. Can you can you share what
happened as you as you experienced it?
>> I can't, man. I'm trying I'm trying to
focus on uh you know getting drafted and
being excited for that. So apolog
>> the the visit you came here was that a
local day or what was were the like how
did you get invited out?
>> Uh it it was a local day for a lot of
other guys but I was a top 30 visit.
>> Okay. How do you think Zachariah and
Georgia prepared you to be ready for,
you know, this moment and to be here for
the Falcons?
>> Yes, they prepared me a lot. um you know
just big thanks to the coaches and
everybody throughout the organization
who you know just put me in the right
positions um you know throughout that
whole year and the way that coach Smart
just goes about the program um you know
he holds everyone accountable not just
the players but the coaches as well so
um shout out my guy coach Kohley did a
great job you know getting me prepared
um you know learning the offense things
like that Luke Corner Javon Williams
there's a lot of guys that you know went
into making my process at Georgia pretty
easy um and and I'm very grateful for
them so I feel They allowed me to have a
lot of different resources to, you know,
use throughout the whole year and be
consistent. I found a consistent routine
that worked for myself and I plan on
using that. Um, it's crazy because now
I'm still in Atlanta. I have my recovery
guy already in Atlanta. Like I I got
everything there that I already did at
Georgia. So, it it's just a blessing,
man. So, so shout out Georgia for, you
know, allowing me to do so and and just
stay stay on that track and get a
routine for myself.
Who who else is there besides a recovery
guy on your on your team?
>> I apologize. You said what?
>> You mentioned your recovery guy. Are
there other people kind of on the team
that that you use to to help take care
of you, keep your body, right?
>> Uh yes. Uh you know, I had a recovery
guy. I have O2 oxygen. Um you know,
they're a great spot as well. You know,
it's like oxygen therapy. Get a chance
to speed up the the blood cells and
recovery process within your body. Um
you know, and then it helps you with
conditioning as well. So, um, you know,
I have them. They were in Athens, but
I'm pretty sure they're it's going to be
pretty easy for them to, you know,
figure something out, um, since I'm
still in in in Georgia. And then, uh,
you know, got a chiropractor and things
like that. And, um, you know, probably
going to add on to to nutrition, um, as
well. So, pretty much have everything
everything accessed, you know, in
Georgia. A lot of relationships built
and and I'm excited to continue those.
>> What up, man? It's Sh
>> going on. How you doing, man? Yes, sir.
What up, boy? Uh,
>> I know you, uh, enjoyed the
conversations you have talking to
different teams. What stood out to you
the most when you got to sit down with
the Dirty Birds, man?
>> Man, I think it was just the genuiness
of everybody. Uh, you know, like I said,
I could just be myself the whole time
and that was something that was
important for me. Um, you know, just to
be able to be in an organization who who
would would love me for me. Um, you
know, and allow me to be myself and
along with uh, you know, utilize me the
right way as possible as well too to be
as successful as possible. Um, but I
just love how genuine the coaches were.
Um, you know, and I feel like they were
they were chill person, like
personalitywise, like they gonna let you
be yourself, but when it come down to
that business, like, yeah, you better be
on your business. And that's how I am.
Like, I like to be myself, but when it
when it really come down to it, like I'm
not playing no games. So, I think we we
kind of bonded with with uh with the
mindset that we have along those lines
and and everybody wants to work together
to help each other out. So, so I love
that about them.
>> What's your message, too? What's the
message to the fans, man? I know you're
a guy who uh love playing to the fans
and uh having a good time for fans who
may not know what Zack Branch is all
about. What would you say to those fans
who are getting ready to get to know who
you are?
>> Yeah, I just say uh stay tuned, man. I'm
excited for the opportunity. Um excited
to stay in Atlanta. um you know and I
want you guys to uh make sure y'all have
fun um you know supporting us and and I
just want to uh say that you going to
get a consistent person, consistent
player, somebody who's disciplined and
real serious about their craft. So um I
that's all I want to say to them. So
appreciate you guys.
>> A lot's been said about your ability in
the the offensive game, but your ability
in special teams as well. Tell us a
little bit about what you can bring as a
return man.
>> Yes, I think I can bring a lot of
different aspects overall, you know, on
offense and special teams like you said.
Um those moments are definitely super
important to be able to flip the
momentum of a game. Um you know,
somebody may have just scored a
touchdown and then they do a kick return
or whatever the case is and sure you
take it to the house or you take it past
the 50. Now it's like dang like they
just switch the whole momentum of the
game. Like the whole the sideline that
can do something to a sideline. So um
whatever position the coaches want me to
be in, you know, to contribute to the
team and I'm all about winning. Um you
know, that's that's what I loved about
Georgia as well. everybody loves about
um you know trying to win and things
like that. So you know whatever position
they want me to be in to be able to help
our team win is is what I'm going to do.
So the special teams receiver, I'm with
it all.
>> And the NFL has the the kind of the
wonky return rules. I mean I mean what
are you expecting from that?
>> Yeah. Um you know I'm I really like to
apply myself. So, I'm going to learn all
the rules and things like that and take
a lot of time to, you know, learn the
ins and outs of that and then, you know,
use the events as well, you know, to try
to learn to see their experiences. Um,
you know, because they were once in
college where the rules were different,
um, at kick return and then their
transition to the NFL or even they were
in the NFL and it was before the rules
and then now it's new rules. So, just
trying to learn from a lot of different
people. Um, it's something that's
important for me and then um, you know,
just try to be the best version of
myself every chance I get.